Peter.
Hey.
- 요원님
- 닐
Mm.
It's late.
Yeah.
- 늦은 시간인데요
- 그래
That's not supposed to be
one of Monet's lost frames?
이거 없어진 모네
그림은 아니겠지?
No, just trying
to clear my head.
아뇨, 그냥 머리를
좀 식히려고요
Good. About that.
좋아, 얘기가 나왔으니
Vincent Adler...
빈센트 애들러
Seven years ago,
he ran a huge Ponzi scheme
7년 전에 커다란
횡령사기를 치고
10억달러와 함께
사라진 남자지
and disappeared
with a billion dollars.
You knew him?
아는 사람이냐?
He's the man who made me
who I am today.
지금의 저를 만든 사람이죠
Mm-hmm. He's rained hell
down on both our lives.
우리 둘 모두를 무지
힘들게 한 사람이지
You knew. You knew, and you
didn't say anything?
알고 있으면서 나한테
일언반구도 없냐?
저도 금방 알았다고요, 네?
I just figured it out
myself, okay?
I'm trying to reconcile
the Adler I knew
제가 알고 있던 애들러가
일을 꾸민 사람이라는게...
with the man responsible for...
- 케이트, 모지 전부?
- 네
For Kate? For Mozzie?
Yeah.
So let's get him.
그럼 놈을 잡자고
Come on.
어서
Start talking.
얘기 시작해봐
Yeah, I'm not much of a beer drinker, so...
I know.
- 전 맥주 안 마셔요
- 알아
그래서 이걸 가지고 왔지
That's why I brought you this.
Oh. I don't recognize
the bottle.
처음 보는 와인이네요
That's because it cost
as much as the beer.
맥주랑 가격이 같은 거니까
와, 코르크 따개도
필요없네요
Wow. I don't even need
a corkscrew.
Nope.
그럼
좋아
Okay.
Now...
이제
How do you know Adler?
애들러는 어떻게 알았어?
얘기하자면 길어요
It's a long story.
내가 널 잡은 것처럼
이 놈을 잡을 거라면
If we are gonna catch this guy,
just like I caught you,
I need to know everything.
전부 다 알아야 한다고
There's too much to tell.
얘기가 길다니까요
You're gonna plead the Fifth?
묵비권 행사하시겠다?
A few secrets are good, Peter...
비밀이 있는 것도 좋죠
- 미스터리하잖아요
- 알겠다
Keeps the mystery alive.
I get it.
This story includes some stuff
이야기 안에 내가 모르는
범죄 건수가 있는거지
about crimes
I don't know about.
Yeah.
그래
No. You're not
holding back on me.
안돼, 나한테 뭘
숨기려고 들어
We've got all night.
I'll make you a deal.
밤새 얘기하면 되지
나랑 거래를 하자
Full immunity
for anything you say
완벽하게 면책권을 줄게
from this moment until the sun
rises over that balcony.
지금부터 해가 뜰때까지
얘기하는 건 전부 다 말야
Full immunity?
완벽한 면책권이요?
Did you kill anybody?
사람 죽였냐?
No.
Then full immunity.
- 아뇨
- 그럼 완벽하게 줄게
Hmm.
All right.
Let's start with this.
좋아요, 이 얘기부터 하죠
Mozzie decoded the music box.
모지가 뮤직박스의
암호를 해독했어요
방정식이었어요
It's an equation.
This is what it built.
그걸로 만들어진 게 이거고요
It's a fractal.
프랙탈이네
잘 아시네요
저도 본 적 있어요
Very good.
I've seen one like it before.
- Where? - In Vincent Adler's office
when I worked for him.
- 어디서?
- 제가 일하던 애들러 사무실요
How did you meet him?
어떻게 만난 건데?
If you want
to know about Adler,
놈에 대해서 알고 싶으시면
모지 이야기를 해야 해요
we got to start with Mozzie.
Why am I not surprised?
왜 놀랍지도 않을까?
8년 전이였어요
It was eight years ago.
I was new to the city,
뉴욕에 갓 올라와서
동쪽 서쪽 구분도 못했죠
didn't know the East Village
from the West.
All right, follow the lady.
좋아, 숙녀를 찾아요
숙녀만 찾으면 됩니다
All you got to do
is follow the lady.
빨리 섞어도 눈만
빠르면 돈을 땁니다
I mix them fast, but if your
eyes are faster, you win...
참 쉽죠잉
Simple as that.
Lady's in the middle.
가운데요
눈 한번 좋네요
두배로 거실래요?
You got good peepers, pal.
Want to double up, buddy?
Sure. Toss them.
그러죠, 섞어봐요
보이는 것 같아도
그렇지 않습니다
Okay. You think you can follow them,
but I'm saying that you can't.
아저씨랑 나만의 대결이죠
It's all a game
of you vs. me.
All right, here we go,
here we go.
좋아요, 갑니다, 갑니다
Where is she?
어딨을까?
어딨나?
잘 봐요, 잘 보라고요
Watch her. Watch her.
잘 숨어 다녀도 아저씨들
좋아하는 숙녀에요
She's a sneaky lady,
but I think she likes you.
오른쪽이요
She's on the right.
가운데에 있는데요
No, she's back in the middle.
Are you crazy?
She's definitely on the right.
미쳤어요? 오른쪽이라니까
야, 이 형씨 돈이거든
Hey.
It's his money, kid.
Crap.
젠장
형씨 몰래 돌아다니네
Ah, she's sneaking around
on you, boss.
재수 좋네
Lucky guess.
You're so good at this,
그렇게 잘하면 직접
걸어보지 그래요?
why don't you put
your own money down?
- 걸거요, 말거요?
- 아저씨!
You gonna bet or walk away.
You!
그래, 그래
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What you got?
어쩌시게?
All right.
좋아요
$50? Come on,
really take this guy.
50불? 제대로 해봐요
Time to put up or shut up, kid.
걸든지 가든지, 형씨
It's up to you.
형씨 알아서 해
All right.
좋아요, 500불로 갑시다
Let's go $500.
이제 말 좀 통하네
Now we're talking.
All right.
All right, looks like
I hooked me a whale here.
좋습니다, 큰 손이 오셨네
Yeah.
잘 좀 봐봐요
Looky, looky, looky,
돈 놓고 돈 먹기
hey, diddle, diddle,
the queen's in the middle.
Follow her fast.
Follow her slow.
빨리 봤다가
천천히 봤다가
내 손은 빨라도
형씨 눈은 느리지
My hands are fast.
Your eyes are slow.
See her? Huh? See her?
보이나? 응? 보여?
Pick that little lady
and you win, my man.
숙녀만 찾으면
돈을 따가요
숙녀만 찾아서 보이면
All you got to do is show me
the smile on the lady's face,
다 갖고 간다 이 말이요
and you walk away with it all.
Ah! You sure?
Yeah. He's sure.
- 확실해요?
- 확실하네
I'm sure.
확실해요
Fun game, man.
재밌네, 고맙습니다
진짜 잘 돌리시네
Thank you. You toss the broads
really well.
Damn it!
젠장!
Cado, you want to earn 10 bucks?
$20.
- 케이도, 10불 벌래?
- 20불 줘요
Seriously?
- 진짜로?
- 이번에도 떼먹으려고?
You gonna stiff me this time?
Go, you little weasel.
Follow that guy.
빨리 가, 조그만 게
저 남자 뒤쫓아가봐
내 훈련 프로그램에
같이 있는 애야
He's in my training program.
I'm the guy from the park.
아까 공원에서
만난 사람인데
병원 신세 지게
하려고 온 거 아냐
Hey, I'm not here to give you
hospital time, kid.
Good, 'cause I'm not giving you
your money back.
잘됐네, 돈은 안 돌려줄 거거든
Ah, keep it.
아, 그냥 넣어둬
What's your angle?
무슨 꿍꿍인데?
Look, I been running
find-the-lady for years,
이봐
내가 그 장사를 몇년 했지만
형씨 바꿔치는 건 못봤어
and even I didn't catch
that swap.
Uh-huh.
Where's your partner?
동업자는 어디가고?
I left him.
Why?
- 내가 떠났어
- 왜?
I need an upgrade.
업그레이드가 필요해서
Mozzie had a goatee?
모지가 염소수염을?
Well, only to distract
from his toupee.
가발에서 시선을
분산시키려고요
Ooh.
Oh, we talked.
얘기를 나눴죠
모지는 디트로이트
살던 이야기를 했죠
Moz told me
about his Detroit days.
어렸을 때부터 길바닥에서
사기를 치고 다녔대요
He'd been running street cons
since he was a kid.
나 안 놀라는 거 봐라
Mm. Notice my lack
of surprise.
이게 다 애들러랑
무슨 상관인데?
What does any of this
have to do with Adler?
모지가 저를 찾은게
그 사람 때문이거든요
Well, he's the reason
Mozzie found me.
이 위조 정말 섬세한데
These forgeries are exquisite.
누가 위조래?
Who says it's a forgery?
Uh, given your living
conditions, I do.
너 사는 꼬라지
봤거든, 위조잖아
How did you match
the tricolor seal?
삼색 인장은 어떻게 맞춘 거야?
Just eyeballed it.
그냥 보고 했는데
By eye?
Mm-hmm.
눈으로?
Huh. You are
very talented, kid.
너 진짜 재능있구나
With you as my partner,
네가 내 파트너가 되면
길바닥 사기치던
날들을 벗어나는 거지
we could move way beyond
the street hustle.
What did you have in mind?
뭘 할 생각인데?
장기적인 건수
A long con,
which, if executed properly,
제대로만 된다면
6개월도 안되서
would enable us
to purchase and retire
on neighboring temperate-zone
islands in a mere six months.
온대지방 섬 근처를
사서 퇴직할 수 있다고
뉴욕 온지도 얼마 안됐고
퇴직하기엔 좀 어린데
I just got to this city,
and I'm too young to retire.
I'm talking about summiting
the Everest of swindles.
사기의 최고봉들이
정상회담을 여는 급이라고
Who's the mark?
목표가 누군데?
Vincent Adler?
빈센트 애들러?
Yeah.
Oh.
네
Now this is getting good.
이제야 재밌어지네
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
영자막 제공★그림자
한글자막 DC 미드갤 SNL
WHITECOLLAR
S02E11 Forging Bonds
Created by JEFF EASTIN
ORIGINAL AIR DATE 2011/01/25
애들러의 이름을
그 때 처음 들었죠
It was the first time I heard
Adler's name.
What?
Mm.
왜요?
Those bonds... that's the first
time I'd come across you.
그 채권 말야, 너를
처음 알게 된 때거든
Really?
Mm-hmm.
정말요?
Tell me.
얘기해주세요
You're stalling.
시간 끄는 거지
아니에요, 해 뜰 때까지
시간 많이 있잖아요
No, I'm not.
Come on.
We got... we got
a long time until sunrise.
맥주도 많고 이...것도
많이 있고, 어서요
We got plenty of beer
and...this. So tell me.
Did you have to fight
to take my case?
제 사건 맡으시려고
막 싸우고 그랬어요?
그럼, 완전 난리였지
Yeah.
It was a real tug-of-war.
Here's another one
for you, Peter.
한 건 더 있어, 피터
새 사건들 모으지 좀 마, 버크
Stop hoarding
all the new cases, Burke.
Bond forgery
sent over from NYPD.
NYPD가 보낸
채권 위조 건이네
아틀란틱 사 위조채권이
6개월 사이에 두 장이네
Two phony Atlantic incorporated
bonds in six months.
What? You want it?
왜, 맡을래?
Two in half a year?
Mm-hmm.
반년에 두장?
아틀란틱 채권위조는
이 번이 처음이잖아
Atlantics
have never been forged.
I'll pass.
난 통과
All right.
그래라
Wow.
This is quality work.
와, 실력 좋은데
냉장고에 붙은
우리 애 그림도 좋아
Mm, so is my kid's drawing
on the fridge.
He's all yours.
- 네가 다 맡아
- 그래
Okay.
I think this guy has a future.
미래가 창창한 놈이네
What was my nickname?
제 별명은 뭐였어요?
What?
뭐?
왜 그래요, 사건마다
별명 다 지으시잖아요
Come on. Every case
gets a nickname.
헤이건은 정체가 드러나기
전까지는 더치맨이였고요
Hagen was the Dutchman
before you I.D.'d him.
- 제 거는요?
- 아, 기억 안나
What was my nickname?
Oh, don't recall.
Oh, that's too bad.
아, 안타깝네요
Well, the sooner you remember,
the sooner we can move on.
빨리 기억해내실 수록
이야기도 빨리 나올 겁니다
James Bonds.
제임스 본드
(bond; 채권)
본드
Bonds.
- 제임스 본드
-제임스 본드
James Bonds. James Bonds.
- 이야
- 그래
Yes, yes.
Would you like another beer?
Yeah.
- 한 병 더 하실래요?
- 그러지 뭐
섞지 말고 흔들어서요?
(본드의 마티니 주문)
Shaken, not stirred?
Oh, see, I knew it was
a mistake telling you.
내 이럴 줄 알았다니까
야, 정말이야
Believe me,
yours was just one file
네 사건은 높이 쌓인
파일 중 하나였을 뿐이라고
in a giant stack of cases.
Yeah.
알겠어요
But it was on top.
제일 위에 있긴 했죠
You weren't that good.
너 그 정도로 실력이
좋지는 않았다고
This guy's good.
이 놈 실력 쩌는데
Honey, come on...
Are we gonna put this away,
여보, 이거 안 치울 거야?
커피 테이블로 쓰게?
or is that
our new coffee table?
Oh, I'm sorry.
아, 미안
이번 건은 왜 그렇게
신경이 쓰이는 건데?
What about this one
is getting under your skin?
You really want to hear
about this?
진짜 들어보고 싶어?
- 그럼, 당연하지
- 좋아
Well, of course, always.
All right.
Satchmo!
사치모
연방수사 증거를
훼손하고 있네
He's tampering
with federal evidence.
Wow.
That's a forgery?
와, 이게 위조야?
The seal, the signature,
the security strip.
인장, 서명
보안용 섬유까지
See, most forgers are
only experts at one aspect.
대부분의 위조가들은
한 측면에만 전문이거든
The man who forged this bond
is capable of bigger things.
이 걸 위조한 녀석은
뭔가 큰 걸 터트릴만 해
He can do it all.
전부 가능하거든
Well, so can you.
당신도 그렇잖아
Mm.
Mnh.
Lose the 'stache?
수염 밀까?
응, 미안해, 매그넘
그래도 사랑해
Yeah, sorry, Magnum.
I still love you.
I love you, too.
나도 사랑해
사치모, 사모님이
이름 지으신 거죠?
Satchmo...
Elizabeth named him?
How do you know I didn't?
내가 아닌 줄
어떻게 알고?
옛날 재즈 팬이시잖아요
요원님은 아니고
Well, Elizabeth likes old jazz.
You don't.
Don't forget
I knew a fair amount about you
다 끝나기 전에 저도
꽤나 알고 있었다고요
before it was over.
Hmm. Know thine enemy.
지피지기 말이냐?
Know thyself, and you will win
a hundred battles.
지피지기면 백전백승이죠
Mozzie's influence?
모지 영향이냐?
Big student of history.
Uh-huh.
역사 좋아했거든요
Tell me how you went
after Adler.
애들러를 어떻게
쫓았는지 말해봐
He was a big fish.
놈은 거물이었죠
There he is, our white whale.
저기 있네, 우리 거물양반
What did you find out
about him?
뭐 좀 알아낸 거 있어?
Well, he's the C.E.O.
of Adler Financial Management,
애들러 금융의 CEO고
회사의 최고 헤지펀드를 굴려
and he runs
their top hedge fund.
좋아, 얼마나 벌었어?
Good.
What'd he bring in?
I don't know.
모르겠는데
절대 그런 말마
전부 알고 있으라고
Never say that.
Know everything.
애들러는 작년에
1억 5천만불을 벌었어
Adler made $150 million
last year,
지난해에 비해서
8%나 더 번 거지
up 8% from the prior year.
지피지기면 백전백승
손자님의 말씀
Know thine enemy,
and you will win... Sun Tzu.
좋아, 어떻게 할 건데?
All right.
What's the con?
Well, Adler routes a hefty
percentage of his profits
애들러는 자기 이윤의
상당부분을 6개월마다
케이맨 제도의
계좌로 송금해
into an account in the Caymans
every six months.
- 세금 피하려고?
- 그렇지
Tax-free?
Exactly.
All we need to reroute
his next wire transfer
다음 번 송금을
다른 데로 돌리려면
딱 두가지가 필요해
is two pieces of information...
Account number and password.
계좌번호랑 비밀번호지
That's where you come in.
네가 알아내야 하고
Where does he keep it...
어디다 보관하는데?
개인금고? 은행 개인금고?
Personal safe, deposit box?
In his head. He's too smart
to keep it anywhere else.
자기 머리 속에 있지
딴 곳에 둘만큼 안 멍청해
가서 물어볼 순 없잖아
불가능하다고
I can't just walk up and ask him for it.
That's impossible.
현자가 말하길 불가능에
도전하는 건 재밌다고 했어
A wise man once said it's fun
to do the impossible.
- 버트런드 러셀?
- 월트 디즈니야
Bertrand Russell?
Walt Disney.
책 좀 더 읽어야겠다
You should read more.
Our clock is five months.
우리에게 있는
시간은 5개월이야
You'll ingratiate yourself,
become a trusted friend,
환심을 사란 말이야
믿음직한 친구가 돼
then convince him to tell you.
그 다음에 말해달라고
설득을 하는 거지
Why don't you do it?
왜 네가 안하고?
난 뒤에 물러서있는
스타일에 가깝거든
I'm more
the behind-the-scenes guy.
All right, look at me,
and then look in the mirror.
좋아, 날 봐
그리고 거울을 봐
Who has a better chance
of charming Adler
금요일에 있을 자선만찬에서
놈을 누가 더 잘 구워삶겠어?
at the charity dinner
on Friday?
The antiquities recovery
project?
유물 복원 프로젝트?
It's five grand a plate.
I can't afford that.
인당 5천불이잖아
그런 돈 없어
Well, you can if you cash in
a few more of your bonds.
네 채권 몇 장 더
교환하면 되잖아
Big mistake.
크나큰 실수네
그 채권들 교환하는 건
계산된 위험요소였다고요
Cashing those bonds
was a calculated risk.
애들러한테 칠 사기를
생각하면 가치가 있었죠
But it was worth it for the con we were
about to run on Adler.
그렇긴 하지만 덕분에
처음으로 네 얼굴을 찾았지
Yeah, but bankrolling them
got us our first visual on you.
If I recall,
제 기억에는 그 날 저만
실수한게 아니었는데요
I wasn't the only one who made
a mistake that day.
- 잠깐만, 잠깐
- 맞다, 그렇죠
No, hang on, hang on.
Yeah.
미드타운에 있는
은행이었죠
Yeah, it was that bank
in Midtown.
Hey.
Did you get it?
- 교환했어?
- 응
Yep.
The teller was a sweetheart.
은행원이 친절하더라고
Oh, she gave you a sucker.
오, 사탕도 주셨네
You know, the irony of that
앨라니스 모리셋 노래스럽네
(ironic; 모리셋 히트송)
would not be lost
on Alanis Morissette.
This guy's a forger.
He's good.
실력 좋은 위조가에요
What?
- 왜?
- 브룩스브라더스 수트야
Shh.
Brooks Brothers suit.
- 알겠습니다
- 그래서?
Yes, I understand.
So?
FBI란 소리야
점장이랑 얘기하잖아
So that means fed...
Talking to the bank manager.
가야겠다
We got to go.
보시게 되면, 곧바로
저한테 연락주십시오
...These bonds, I want you
to call me immediately.
FBI는 본 적 없는데
Never met a fed before.
계속 그렇게 두자고
Let's keep it that way.
가능하시다면
잡아두시고요
Detain him if possible.
- 당연하죠
- 좋습니다
Absolutely.
Good.
Excuse me.
실례합니다
엿들어서 죄송한데요
FBI요원이세요?
Sorry, I-I couldn't help but
overhear. Are you with the FBI?
특수요원 피터버크입니다
Special agent Peter Burke.
와
Wow.
금방 은행에서 돈을 찾았는데
I-I just took some money
out of the bank,
위조 이야기를 하시길래요
and I heard you talking
about counterfeiting.
그 쪽 돈은 괜찮습니다
위조채권 사건이거든요
Your money's safe. I'm looking
after counterfeit bonds.
집에 채권이 좀 있는데
가짜인지 어떻게 아나요?
Well, I have some bonds
at home.
How would I know
if they're not real?
I'm sure they're fine.
괜찮으실 겁니다
Well, thanks again for all the hard
work you're doing, agent Burke.
여튼 노고에 감사드려요
버크 요원님
That's for you.
Have a good day.
이거 드세요
좋은 하루 되시고요
He's not a nanny goat
in a petting zoo.
만지는 동물원에 있는
염소가 아니거든
FBI라고
He's a fed.
몇 분만 기다리면
다섯 블록 안에다가
Within minutes, he could have
set up a five-block perimeter...
트렌치 코트입은
요원을 풀 수도 있다고
Hundreds
of trench-coated G-men.
It was worth it.
We now know two things.
그럴 가치가 있었어
이제 두가지나 알았다고
채권을 옮겨야 된단 거랑
이름이 피터버크라는 거
We got to move off bonds,
and his name is Peter Burke.
Know thy enemy, right?
지피지기라며?
Fine.
알았어
이제 초대장을 살
돈이 생겼으니
Now you've got the money
to pay for the invitation.
What name you gonna use?
어떤 이름으로 가게?
I don't know.
글쎄
Halden.
홀든 법무 법인
신용문제 해결
홀든
Nicholas Halden.
니콜라스 홀든
Quaint.
기발하네
가명은 여러 개 만들어
필요하게 될테니까
Get yourself a few aliases.
You're gonna need them.
Oh, pop quiz, hot shot...
깜짝퀴즈 맞춰봐
애들러의 예방적
시장 전략은?
Adler's market strategy
pre-crash?
파생상품은 짧게
오름세에 있는 상품으로
Short derivatives,
bullish on commodities.
Mm. You have learned much,
grasshopper.
많이 배웠네, 풋내기
그 싸구려 와인은
왜 그 병에 채워?
Why are you filling that bottle
with bargain red?
Have you studied
Adler's wine list?
애들러 와인리스트 공부했어?
Is that the '91 Bordeaux?
91년산 보르도?
잘못된 병에 담긴
바로 그 해지
The one year it was corked
in the wrong bottle.
$800 a pop.
한 잔에 800불이야
I, of course, got this bottle empty.
난 당연히 빈 병을 구했지
Best served
when the guests are drunk.
손님들이 취했을 때
제일 잘 나가거든
And I asked my cleaner
to keep an eye out
네 사이즈로 찾아달라고
세탁소에 부탁했어
for something in your size.
그게... 나한테
수트는 좀 아닌데
Yeah, I don't know
if I'm a suit guy.
Ah, you'll be fine.
괜찮을 거야
Well, I really
appreciate you coming. Thanks.
와주셔서 감사합니다
Mr. Adler?
애들러 씨?
Nick Halden.
Nice to meet you.
닉 홀든입니다
만나서 반갑습니다
I brought this
from my collection.
제 콜렉션에서
가지고 와봤는데요
That's very generous.
Thanks for coming.
인심이 후하시네요
와주셔서 감사합니다
Hey, nice play on the emerging
markets last quarter.
지난 분기 이머징마켓 건
정말 멋지셨습니다
You really called Russia.
러시아는 정확하셨어요
- 결국 곡물이니까요
- 그렇죠
Well, it all came down to grains, didn't it?
Yeah.
Where do you think
they're going?
어느 쪽이라고
생각하시는데요?
Bull market.
활황장세겠죠
For us, not Europe.
저희 쪽이요
유럽 말고요
I'd say their imports
are up 20%.
그 쪽 수입이
20%정도 오르겠죠
Interesting.
Enjoy the party.
흥미롭네요
즐기다 가세요
Raphael's Saint George and the Dragon...
라파엘 작품이네요
"성 게오르기우스와 용"
It's a powerful piece.
강렬한 작품이죠
상품시장과 예술이라
관심사가 넓으시네요
Commodities and art?
You've got diverse interests.
Like you, art is my passion.
애들러 씨처럼
예술에 열광하거든요
Then you should talk
to my assistant.
제 비서와 이야기를
나누셔야겠군요
Nick Halden.
닉 홀든 씨야
Hi.
안녕하세요
I'm Kate Moreau.
케이트 모로에요
Hi.
안녕하세요
You like it?
마음에 드세요?
네? 아, 네...
What? What?
Oh, yeah.
그럼요, 아니...
No, it's, uh...
It's breathtaking.
숨을 멎게 하네요
제가 제일 좋아하는
작품이에요
It's my favorite one.
라파엘로는 균형의 대가였죠
Raphael was a master
of balance...
thick brush strokes
for the landscape,
풍경을 그릴 때는
붓질이 두껍지만
피부 톤은 거의...
반투명하거든요
but the skin tones
are almost...translucent.
Are you an artist?
예술가신가요?
I dabble.
끄적거리는 정도죠
I tried,
전 노력은 해봤는데
but the romance
of being a starving artist
배고픈 예술가에 대한
환상은 금방 가시더라고요
wore off very fast.
Well, you won't find
any original Nick Haldens
시내 갤러리에 그림이
없는 건 마찬가지니까요
at a gallery downtown.
무슨 일 하시는데요?
What do you do?
I'm looking
for new opportunities.
새로운 기회를
찾아보는 중이죠
실례합니다
제가 가져가도?
Excuse me, sir.
May I take that?
Oh. Thank you.
아, 고마워요
You're here to cozy up
to my boss.
사장님한테 아부하러
오신 분이군요?
If I work for Adler,
I can go anywhere.
애들러 씨 밑에서 일하면
어디든 갈 수 있으니까요
Any advice?
해주실 말이라도?
I've seen the seating chart,
and you're nowhere near him.
좌석표를 봤는데
가깝지는 않으시던데요
That's your first challenge.
그게 첫번째 도전과제겠죠
안녕
Hi.
저 도전 좋아합니다
I like a challenge.
행운을 빌어요, 닉
Good luck, Nick.
Thanks.
고마워요
빈센트 애들러
제네비브 칼슨
닉 홀든
It seems my date
제 데이트가 아르헨티나
테이블로 쫓겨났네요
has been relegated
to the Buenos Aires table.
샐러드가 나오기 전에
원하는 걸 말하세요
You have until
the salad course arrives
to tell me what you want.
Go.
시작
당신 밑에서
일하고 싶습니다
I want to work for you.
무슨 능력으로요?
In what capacity,
곡물과 그림을 향한
그 쪽의 열정 말고요
other than your enthusiasm
for grains and paint?
인수요
Acquisitions.
우리 팀 꽉 찼습니다
My team is full.
Cameron Singer...
You're about to buy his firm.
캐머론 싱어의 회사
인수예정이시죠?
Speculation's been front page
of the Journal all week.
월스트리트저널에
일주일동안 기사 났죠
빵 좀 줘요
Pass the bread.
Well, he's been avoiding
that woman.
저 여성분을 계속
피하고 계시더라고요
Hannah Fields?
한나 필즈요?
다음 주에 필즈가 새 투자
지점을 발표한다더군요
Next week, Hannah Fields
will announce
her new investment branch.
She's buying out Singer.
싱어를 빼내려는 겁니다
싱어가 발을 빼게 되면
언론에서 물고 늘어질테고
He's gonna
back out of your deal,
and the media will eat it up.
사장님 회사도
불안정해지겠죠
Your company
will appear unstable.
그러면 투자자도
놀라서 빠지겠죠
That could spook investors.
I'm gonna continue my meal now
이제 당신보다 드레스가
더 잘 어울리는 분과
with someone who looks better
in an cocktail dress than you.
식사를 마저 해야겠네요
싱어를 잘 감시하세요
Well, look into Singer.
If it turns out I'm right,
call me.
제 말이 맞는다면
연락주시고요
The Singer deal...
was it true?
싱어 이야기..,
진짜였냐?
그럼요, 모지랑 제가
몇주동안 감시했다고요
Absolutely. Mozzie and I had
been spying on them for weeks.
애들러는 싱어를 버리고
한 달 뒤에 절 찾았죠
Adler ditched Singer
and brought me in a month later.
매물을 살펴보라고
널 고용한 거구나
He hired you to find things
for him to buy.
제 일 중 하나가
애들러가 만나는
Well, part of my job
was knowing everything
모든 사람에 대해서
모든 걸 알아내는 거였죠
about everyone
Adler dealt with.
재산도 적도 많았거든요
He had a lot of holdings
and a lot of enemies.
Turns out I had a knack
for rooting them out.
알고보니 저한테 그런 걸
고르는 재능이 있더라고요
And Kate was there
the whole time.
케이트는 계속
옆에 있었고 말야
Mm-hmm.
Is that when you guys
got together?
그 때부터 만난 거냐?
아뇨, 아뇨
남자친구 있었어요
No, no.
She had a boyfriend.
Hmm. Oh.
거기 없어요
It's not there.
다시 해보면 되죠
All right, we'll just have
to try again.
Remind me again why I let you
제가 왜 그 쪽이 이러게
뒀는지 다시 말해줄래요?
make my favorite necklace
disappear.
Because...You like magic.
왜냐면...
마술 좋아하시니까요
Someday you're going to tell me
all of your secrets.
언젠가는 비밀을
다 털어놔야할 거에요
I mean it.
정말이에요
May I?
해도?
Maybe someday.
아마도 언젠가는요
Come out with me on Friday.
금요일에 저랑 데이트해요
I, um... I have
your assignment from Adler.
애들러 씨가 맡기신
업무가 있어요
He wants you to look into this.
그 쪽이 살펴보라고 하셨어요
Right.
그렇군요
Looks like someone's been looking into his
recent art acquisitions.
누군가 최근에 수집한
예술품 목록을 뒤졌나본데요
닉?
Nick?
Michael asked me to move
to Chicago with him.
마이클이 시카고로
같이 가자고 했어요
Chicago?
시카고요?
Are you gonna go?
가실 거에요?
Um, I-I am, in a month.
갈 거에요, 한 달 후에
It's a big step.
큰 결정이네요
Yeah. I know.
그러게요
저도 알아요
Well, you'll like Chicago.
시카고 맘에 드실 거에요
They, uh...
They have a great art museum,
멋진 미술관도 있고
and decent pizza.
피자도 맛있고요
Little windy.
바람은 좀 불테지만
네, 들었어요
Yeah, I've heard that.
I should just get this...
I need to get back to work.
- 이걸 봐야겠네요
- 일해야겠어요
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
프랙탈이야
수학관련 관심사지
It's a fractal...
a mathematical curiosity.
That was the first time
you'd seen one?
그 때가 처음 본 거라고?
Yeah. You know, he was
obsessed with them.
네, 정말 집착했죠
그때 본 건 비슷하긴 했지만
저거랑 똑같진 않았어요
His were similar to that one,
but none was an exact match.
좋아, 케이트는 딴 남자랑
시카고로 가기로 했었고
Okay, so, Kate was going
to Chicago with another guy,
and you were trying to root out
넌 누가 애들러 물건에 관심을
가지는 지 알아내려고 했다고
whoever was looking
into Adler's stuff.
계속 얘기해 봐
Keep talking.
You found the culprit.
용의자를 찾았다고
She talked her way in.
자기 입으로 말하던데요
남아메리카 쪽 물건에
관심이 제일 크더군요
She seems mostly interested in your
South American acquisitions.
여기로 직접 오게 했고?
And you got her
to come here in person?
그 쪽 조사에 감명받은
재단이 있다고 말했죠
I had the foundation
feed her a story
that they were impressed
with her research.
입사면접인 줄 알고 있습니다
She thinks she's here
for a job interview.
Bring her in.
들여보내
네
Yes, sir.
Miss Hunter.
헌터 씨
알렉스 헌터입니다
Alex Hunter.
- 만나뵙게 되서...
- 앉으시죠
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Have a seat.
Miss Hunter...
헌터 씨
Your passion for antiquities
젊은 여성 치고는 유물에
관심이 대단하시던데요
is unusual
for such a young woman.
Well, every object
has a story to tell.
모든 물건에는 각자의
이야기가 있거든요
전 그런 이야기들에
매력을 느끼고요
I find those stories
fascinating.
That was almost convincing.
거의 속을 뻔 했네요
Who are you working for?
누구 밑에서 일합니까?
I don't work
for anyone...yet.
그런 사람 없는데요
아직까지는요
That's why I'm here.
그래서 여기 온 거고요
연기는 그만하세요
You can drop the act.
Someone is paying you
to get into my records.
누군가 제 기록을
뒤지라고 시켰잖습니까
누군데? 말하지 그래?
Now, who is that?
Why don't you tell me?
- 애들러 씨, 그냥...
- 뭘 찾고 있는 거지?
Sir, maybe it would be best if we...
What are you looking for?
There were rumors you made
some big discoveries.
커다란 발견을 하셨다는
소문이 돌고 있었어요
그래서 궁금했죠
I got curious.
I thought you wanted to share
your art with the world.
애들러 씨께서 세상과
공유하시고 싶으신 줄...
그건 내가 결정할 일이지
That's for me to decide.
You accessed
my private database.
내 개인 데이타
베이스에 접속해서
You made copies of my records.
내 기록들을 복사했으니
I should bring charges.
고소라도 해야겠네요
누구나 인생에서
실수를 한번 하면
Everybody gets
one big mistake in life
and one opportunity to fix it.
되돌릴 수 있는
기회를 한 번 얻죠
전 두번째 기회가 있다고
생각하는 사람입니다
I believe in second chances,
miss Hunter.
무슨 말인지 아실만한
분이라고 생각되네요
I think you're clever enough
to know what I mean.
고맙네, 닉
Thanks, Nick.
제가 감사하죠, 애들러 씨
Grateful to be here,
Mr. Adler.
Vincent.
빈센트라고 불러
Your hard work
deserves a reward.
열심히 일했으니
보상이 있어야지
Thank you.
감사합니다
투자는 허락되지
않은 걸 알지만...
I know I don't meet
the buy-in, but...
왜 그래, 닉
다 끝난 얘기잖아
Nick, come on, now.
We've talked about this.
내가 아는 사람들이
투자하는 거 별로라니까
You know I don't like my people
to invest in the fund.
You've made exceptions.
예외도 있으시잖아요
For you.
너만
Thank you, sir.
감사합니다
놈이랑 같이 투자했구나
You invested
your money with him.
Mm. All of it.
전부 다요
다들 투자했어요
14%나 이익이 났거든요
We all did.
He was making us 14%.
- 사기인 줄 몰랐구나?
- 그럼요
You didn't know it was a scam?
No.
당시 제 목표는 애들러의
믿음을 사는거였으니까요
My goal at the time was
to prove my loyalty to Adler.
일이 제 전부가 됐죠
The job became my life.
알렉스는 어떻게 됐는데?
Then what happened to Alex?
거기도 이야기가
더 있을 것 같은데
I know there's more
to that story.
귀엽기는
You're sweet.
Nice trick.
실력 좋네요
You got me.
날 속여넘기다니
You got off easy.
쉽던데요
사과하긴 늦었어요
Too late to apologize.
사과 안 할 건데요
당신 잡는게 내 일인데
I'm not gonna apologize.
It's my job to catch you.
잡히지 않는 게
그 쪽 일이고요
It's your job
to not get caught.
맞는 말이네요
Fair enough.
What do you want?
뭘 원해요?
Buy me a drink, and we'll talk.
술 한 잔 사요
그럼 말할테니
Let's go.
가시죠
Nick Halden...
That's a good name.
닉 홀든이라
멋진 이름이네
Not your real one,
but I like it.
진짜 이름은 아니어도
맘에 들어
I recognize a fellow grifter
when I see one, Nick.
딱 보면 동료 사기꾼인거
다 보인다고, 닉
All right.
좋아
Humor me, Alex.
말해 봐, 알렉스
진짜 찾고 있던 게 뭐야?
What were you
really looking for?
Something Adler doesn't have.
애들러가 가지고
있지 못한 물건
다 가지고 있는데
He has everything.
이 물건은 없지
He doesn't have this.
It's a music box.
뮤직박스야
Quite the Holy Grail.
퍽이나 귀한 거네
성배만큼 귀한 거야
It's worth about as much.
So Alex turned you on
to the music box.
알렉스가 뮤직박스
이야기를 해준 거구나
네, 몇 년 동안
쫓고 있었거든요
Yeah, she'd been chasing it
for years.
애들러가 정보를 가지고
있다는 소리를 들은 거죠
She heard Adler
had information on it.
Did he?
- 그랬나?
- 소문이 있었죠
He had a rumor that it was
코펜하겐의 아말리엔보르
궁에 다녀갔다고요
at the Amalienborg Palace
in Copenhagen.
Said she'd send me a message
도움이 필요하면 메세지를
모내겠다고 했고요
if she ever needed
my help getting it.
어떤 메세지?
What kind of message?
A flower.
꽃이요
- 보낸 적이 있어?
- 그럼요
Did she ever send it?
Yeah, but that's
another part of the story.
그치만 또 다른 이야기에요
알렉스는 사라졌고
케이트는...
Alex disappeared, and Kate...
Well, things changed.
상황이 변했죠
You're taking a sick day?
병가를 냈다고?
좀 아프지도 못하냐?
I'm not allowed to feel lousy?
애들러와 함께 하는
매일이 중요하다고
Every day with Adler counts.
계좌는 이미 준비됐어
I've already got
the siphon in place.
비밀번호만 있으면 된다고
All we need is the password.
비밀번호 알아낼게
I'll get the password.
네 마음이 완전히
집중 못하는 것 같아
You know, I'm sensing your heart
isn't totally into this.
내 마음은 괜찮아
My heart is fine.
Ah.
This is about the girl.
그 여자애 때문이구나
I thought she left for Chicago.
시카고로 간 줄 알았더니
She left today.
오늘 갔어
이게 최선일 거야
You know,
it's probably for the best.
Now you can focus.
이제 집중할 수 있잖아
끊어야겠다, 알겠지?
I got to go, okay?
Kate?
케이트?
You're supposed to be
in Chicago.
시카고 간다더니
It's a big step...
큰 결정이였어요
잘못된 곳으로요
In the wrong direction.
Why?
왜요?
당신이 여기 있으니까요
Because you're here.
You and Adler developed a connection
애들러와 가까워지고
케이트와 결국
같이하게 된거구나
and you and Kate
were finally together.
You had it all.
다 가졌던 거야
최고급 음식을 먹고
Yeah, I was eating
the best food,
최고급 수트를 입고
최고급 와인을 마셨죠
wearing the best suits,
drinking the best wine...
코르크 있는 와인이요
the kind that has corks.
It was the perfect life.
완벽한 생활이었어요
And it was also
the perfect lie.
완벽한 거짓말이기도 했지
너랑 모지는 아직도
사기를 치는 중이었잖아
You and Mozzie were
still working the long con.
거짓말을 진짜처럼
만드려고 노력했어요
Trying to make the lie real.
But every con has
an expiration date.
그렇지만 모든 사기는
유효기간이 있죠
Adler makes the transfer
on Friday,
애들러가 금요일에
이체를 한다는데
아직도 비밀번호를
못 알아냈잖아
and you still haven't gotten
the password yet.
알아낸다고 했잖아
알아낸다니까
I said I'll get it,
I'll get it.
Oh, good, because I thought
you were having second thoughts
잘됐네, 네가 다른 생각을
하고 있는 줄 알았거든
멋진 라이프스타일 잡지같은
생활을 버리기 싫어서 말야
about abandoning your new
town-and-country lifestyle.
정신차려, 닐
Don't kid yourself.
케이트는 네 진짜 이름도
모르잖아, 아는 사람도 없고
Kate doesn't even know
your real name. None of them do.
날 생각해준다고, 응?
다들 생각해줘
They care about me, okay?
She cares about me.
Um, no.
아닌데
닉 홀든을 생각해주는 거지
있지도 않은 사람을 말야
She cares about Nick Halden,
and he doesn't exist.
FBI가 너에 대해서
묻고 다닌다더라
I hear the suit's
been asking around about you.
He has a sketch.
몽타주도 그렸대
Where'd he get a sketch?
어디서 정보를 얻어서?
몽타주든 지문이든
항상 뭐든 있다고
Oh, they always have a sketch
or a print or something.
Look, it's time to finish
this job and move on.
봐봐, 이제 작업을 마치고
그만 나아갈 시간이여
어떤지 한 번 보자
Let's have a look at you.
Never worn
a custom suit before.
맞춤 수트는 처음이에요
The fit is perfect...
핏이 완벽하네
바짓단은 말고
Except for the cuff.
The break should be an eighth
of an inch above the shoe.
신발 위로 1/8인치어야 해
Nelson.
- 넬슨
- 잘 보셨습니다
Good eye, sir.
I can't accept.
This is a $10,000 suit.
못 받습니다
10만불짜린데요
You can and you will.
그래도 돼
Some people say dress
for the job you want.
사람들은 하고싶은 일에
맞춰서 옷을 입으라지만
난 되고싶은 사람처럼
옷을 입으라고 하지
I say dress as the man
you want to be.
Nick, men like you and I...
We have an obligation
닉, 너나 나같은 사람들은
의무를 지고 있는 거야
기회가 있을 때마다
평범한 걸 떨쳐야한다고
to assault the commonplace
every chance we get,
우리가 입는 옷이나
수집하는 예술품부터
from the clothes we wear
to the art we collect
to the women in our lives.
인생의 여자들까지
You and Kate have gotten close.
케이트랑 가까워졌던데
Yeah.
네
You look good together.
둘이 잘 어울려
How does she feel about it?
케이트는 무슨 생각인가?
There are things about me
that I haven't told her.
저에 대해서 아직 말하지
못한 것들이 있습니다
I wouldn't worry.
나라면 걱정 않겠어
Oftentimes,
the things we try and hide
종종 우리가 숨기려는 게
are the most obvious
to the people around us.
주변 사람들에게 제일
뻔히 보이는 것들이거든
Everything all right?
괜찮나?
Nelson, would you excuse us
for a moment?
넬슨 좀 실례해도 될까요?
Of course.
Thanks.
- 그럼요
- 고맙습니다
There's something
you should know.
아셔야 할 게 있습니다
What's wrong?
무슨 일인데?
I flagged a small irregularity
케이먼 제도에 있는 계좌에
불규칙한 신호가 있었습니다
in your account in the Caymans.
Trace-analysis reports
were inconclusive.
추적 분석을 했더니
확실치는 않더군요
What kind of irregularity?
불규칙한 뭐가?
Blips from a random I.P. address.
랜덤 IP 주소에서
들어오는 신호요
Hacker?
해커인가?
아마 은행 쪽 사람이
확인하는 걸 겁니다
It's probably someone
from the bank, confirming.
But I'd have to look into
the account details to be sure.
그렇지만 확실히 하려면
계좌 사항을 살펴봐야합니다
You'd need the password.
비밀번호가 필요하겠군
I'll arrange a time for us
직접 가셔서 접속하시도록
은행가실 시간을 잡겠습니다
to go to the bank
so you can access it yourself.
No, no.
아냐, 아냐
I trust you.
널 믿으니까
은행은 6시에 닫아
다하면 태워버리고
Bank closes at 6:00.
Burn this when you're done.
Don't sell yourself short.
자기비하는 하지마
Kate'll love you
for who you really are...
케이트는 너란 사람
자체를 사랑해줄테니까
As will others.
다른 사람도 마찬가지고
You like the hat?
모자 맘에 들어?
익숙해질 순 있겠네
I could get used to it.
Are you all dressed up
with somewhere else to go?
이렇게 차려입고
좋은 데라도 가게?
아니, 여섯시 까지
갈 데가 있거든
No, I just have to be
somewhere by 6:00.
오래 전에 한 약속이라
It's a commitment I made
a long time ago.
그 약속은 날리는 게 어때
I think that you should blow off
said commitment.
Yeah?
그래?
봐, 바이올린 연주자도
동의하잖아
Look. Our violinist agrees.
나랑 여기 있는 거야
You are staying here with me.
친구랑 약속한 거야
취소할 수가 없어
I promised a friend. I can't...
I can't back out of it.
Kate, I'm...
케이트 난...
무슨 일이야, 닉?
What's wrong, Nick?
I just feel like...
그냥...
you and me and all this...
I don't know.
너랑, 나, 이 모든게...
나도 모르겠어
I feel like I could blink,
and it'd all be gone.
눈을 감았다 뜨면
다 없어질 것 같아서
You just blinked.
방금 깜박였잖아
I'm still here.
난 아직 있고
Then nothing else matters.
다른 일은 상관없지
비밀번호를 못 찾았다고
You didn't get the password.
네가 말했잖아
장기적인 사기라고
You said it yourself.
This is a long con.
You stepped on the brakes
when you should have leaned in.
속도를 내야할 때
브레이크를 밟은 거야
It's Kate, isn't it?
케이트 때문이지?
I'm in love with her.
케이트를 사랑해
Every con man gets his heart
broken once.
모든 사기꾼은
실연을 당한다고
한번은
케이트는 안 그럴 거야
She's not gonna break my heart.
Well...
뭐...
...We'll get them
next time.
다음 번을 노리지 뭐
Love is a temporary madness.
사랑은 일시적 정신착란이야
It erupts like an earthquake
and then subsides.
지진처럼 터졌다가
가라앉는 거지
St. Augustine.
성 아우구스티노
Good.
You've been reading.
잘했어, 책 좀 읽었네
똑똑한 사람이
그러라고 했거든
A smart guy told me to.
Oh, my God.
아, 하느님
I want more.
- 더 원해
- 뭐?
What?
You're insatiable.
만족할줄을 모르네
Pizza.
피자 말이야
What?
뭐라고?
어제 먹던 마르게리따가
반 남은 거 먹자
We have half a marguerita
left over from last night.
Ah.
Wait, hold on. Whoa...
Who said you get the sheet?
누가 시트 가져가래?
- 안돼, 안돼
- 내가 가져갈 거야
No, no, no, no, no.
Yes, I get it.
All right.
알았어
Mine.
All right.
- 내 거야
- 그래
Oh.
Whew. Wow.
와
Nick.
What?
- 닉
- 왜?
The neighbors can see you.
밖에서 보잖아
Oh.
Hi, neighbors.
아, 안녕
Should I give them
a little show?
쇼를 좀 해줄까?
No. Here.
이거
Look. There.
Ooh, I got a hat, too.
- 자
- 모자도 썼네
이제 좀 보여줄만 하네
Now you're presentable.
All right.
You like that?
맘에 들어?
Put some pants on.
바지나 좀 입어
...Floors of Wall Street.
You got the sheet.
넌 시트 가져갔잖아
마지막 조각은 내 거지
You don't get the last slice.
It's only fair.
그래야 공평하잖아
빈센트 애들러가 사라지자
Vincent Adler has disappeared,
and with him
고객들의 수억달러도
함께 사라졌습니다
hundreds of millions of dollars
of his clients' money.
최초 조사에 따르면
그의 투자회사가
A preliminary investigation
indicates his investment firm
모래성과 같이
부실하다고 합니다
may have been built
on a giant house of cards.
증권감독위는 현재
애들러의 회사가
Securities regulators
now claim
고객 계좌로 어떤 거래도
하지 않았다고 밝혔습니다
Adler never traded
any shares for client accounts.
이게 사실이라면
애들러의 실종은
If true, Adler's disappearance
could prove to be
the brilliant exit strategy
역사상 가장 큰 금융사기를
벌인 범인의 도주로
for one of the greatest
financial frauds of our time.
기록될 수도 있습니다
Holy cow.
Can you believe it?
세상에나, 믿겨져?
Who'd have figured?
누가 알았겠어?
Nobody saw this coming?
Huh.
아무도 몰랐던 거야?
수천명이 평생한 저축이랑
자선모금도 가져갔답니다
This guy took
thousands of people
for their life savings,
including charities.
Clinton Jones.
클린턴 존스입니다
Word around here is
that you're putting together
특수 화이트칼라 수사팀을
꾸리신다고 하더군요
a special white-collar
task force.
I am.
그렇지
Well, I've only been here
a few months.
여기 온지는
몇 달 안됐지만
But I was wondering,
혹시 자리가 있으면
저도 기회가 있나 해서요
if there were some spots open,
if I could get a shot.
Are you the one who put
the Dutchman on our radar?
자네가 우리 쪽 감시망에
더치맨을 올린 사람인가?
Yes, sir. I studied a profile
like his at Quantico.
그렇습니다
콴티코에서 더치맨 같은
범인 프로파일을 공부했습니다
Hmm.
Well, I can't promise anything.
약속을 해 주지는 못해
지원자도 많아
호봉 높은 요원들에...
It is a long list,
agents with more seniority...
어떤지 잘 알잖아
You know how it is.
That's not the same sucker
작년에 제임스 본드가
줬다는 사탕은 아니죠?
you got from James Bonds
last year, is it?
- 얘기가 있거든요
- 그래
People talk.
Yeah.
Well, nobody gets why
I'm still holding on to this.
내가 왜 집착하는지
이해하는 사람은 없지
Unfinished business.
끝내지 못한 일이니까요
I get it.
전 이해합니다
So, Adler disappeared,
but what about his account?
그럼 애들러가 사라지고
계좌는 어떻게 됐어?
There was only a dollar
left in it.
1달러만 들어있더라고요
The password was an anagram
비밀번호는 애너그램이었요
for "nice try Neal."
"좋은 시도야, 닐" 이었죠
케이트랑은 어떻게 됐고?
Then what happened with Kate?
No money, no jobs.
돈도 없고, 직장도 없고
It's all gone.
- 다 없어졌다고
- 알아, 잠깐만
I know. I know.
Hey, hey.
We're gonna be okay.
괜찮아질 거야
It's just you and me now,
right?
이젠 너랑 나뿐이잖아
That's all that matters.
Come here.
그게 중요한 거야
이리 와
We're gonna get it all back,
okay?
다 되찾을 거야, 알았지?
Okay.
알겠어
How?
어떻게?
Okay, if we're gonna do this,
좋아, 우리 계속할 거라면
나에 대해서 알아야할 게 있어
I need to tell you
something about me.
What?
뭔데?
I'm not Nick Halden.
난 닉 홀든이 아니야
My name's Neal Caffrey.
내 이름은 닐 카프리야
You and Kate lost everything.
너랑 케이트는
모든 걸 일었구나
네, 애들러가 월급을
후하게 줬어도
Yeah. Adler paid well.
전부 회사로 다시 들어갔어요
We put it right back
into the company.
왜 안그러겠어요? 손이
닿기만 해도 황금인데
And why not? Everything
he touched turned to gold.
He conned us.
저희한테 사기친거죠
He conned everybody...
And then disappeared.
전부한테 그랬지
그러고는 사라지고
케이트한테 사실을
말하고 나서 어쨌어?
What happened after you
told Kate the truth?
I thought this was about Adler.
애들러 이야기 하시자더니
맥주도 좀 남았고
Well, I just got
a few beers left,
궁금해져서
and I'm curious.
살아남는 법을 가르쳤죠
I taught her to survive.
거기 서!
누가 좀 잡아요!
Hey, you, stop!
Someone stop that guy!
거기 서!
손들어!
Freeze!
Put your hands up!
Hey. Get up.
어이, 일어나
경관님, 이 놈이
제 소포를 훔쳤어요
Officer,
this man stole my package.
내가 안 그랬어
I did no such thing.
조심하세요
Whoa, whoa, be careful
with that.
16세가 팔코너
사본이라고요
It's the Falconer manuscript
from the 16th century.
나 이 놈 알겠는데
Hey, I recognize this guy.
Oh.
How you doing, Smedley?
어떻게 지내, 스메들리?
이 놈 3개 주에서
영장나온 놈이에요
This guy's got warrants out
in three different states.
Thanks to you, we can get him
off the streets.
덕분에 잡아들이게 됐네요
인수증 써 드려
Write him a receipt.
가져가시면 안돼요
값진 물건이라고요
You can't take that.
It's worth a fortune.
저희가 관리하겠습니다
We'll look after you, okay?
23구 경찰서로 이걸
가지고 가세요
Bring this
to the 23rd Precinct.
며칠 뒤에 증거보관소에서
찾아가도록 하세요
Pick it up from evidence in a few days.
Days?!
- 며칠이요?
- 23구에요
23rd.
이럴 때마다 두피
뜯기는 것도 좀 지겹거든
I'm a little sick
of being scalped
every time we pull
one of these.
있지, 모즈, 그거
안쓰는게 더 나아
You know, Moz, you look better
without the hairpiece.
Very handsome.
완전 잘생겼어
헤일 몫을 떼주고
나머지는 셋이 나누자
Hale takes a cut.
We split the rest three ways.
글쎄, 나쁘진 않은데
I don't know.
It's not bad.
To all this.
이 모든 걸 위해
최고의 시간을 위해
To the best of times.
And to...
그리고...
코트 다쥐르의
우리 빌라를 위해
Our villa on the C?e d'Azur,
the sun setting
over the Mediterranean.
지중해 너머로 해가 지고
언덕위로 올리브
나무가 부스럭거리고
The olive trees whispering
in the hills.
하자, 가자고
Let's do it.
Let's go.
Now?
지금?
- 지금 프랑스를 가자고?
- 그래
You want to go to France now?
Yeah.
Look, that FBI agent...
Burke.
그 FBI 요원 말야, 버크
영국 파운드 건을
캐고 다니고 있대
He's been asking around
about the British pounds.
Maybe...
I don't know.
혹시, 글쎄...
좀 쉬는 시간을 갖자고
Maybe we should take
some time away,
FBI의 감시를 벗어나서
outside the FBI's range.
아직 따뜻할 때 앙티브
해변에서 출발하고
We can start in Cap d'Antibes
while it's still warm,
파리까지 올라가서
work our way up to Paris,
암스테르담, 코펜하겐까지
over to Amsterdam,
then Copenhagen.
코펜하겐에는 안갈 거야
I'm not going to Copenhagen.
Okay,
I should've mentioned Alex.
그래, 알렉스 이야기를
했어야 하는데
알렉스 이야기가
아니야, 닐
This isn't about Alex, Neal.
그냥 "케이트, 코펜하겐 가서"
You can't just say, "Hey, Kate,
let's go to Copenhagen
"알렉스가 이야기한 건수를
해보자" 이러지 못했잖아
for this opportunity
Alex told me about."
나를 속이려고 했잖아
You just tried to con me.
내가 실수했어, 응?
I made a mistake, okay?
우리를 위해 하는 거야
I'm doing this for us.
That music box
is worth a fortune.
그 뮤직박스는 값이
엄청 나갈 거야
우리가 원하는 삶을
줄 수 있는 거라고
It can give us
the life we want.
You went to Copenhagen
without her.
케이트 없이
코펜하겐 갔지
네, 박스가 있었으니까요
Yeah.
The box was there.
But it was
a three-person job.
그치만 3인짜리
계획이었어요
Without Kate, it fell apart.
케이트가 없었으니
실패했죠
알렉스는 프랑스 병원에
입원했고, 저도 겨우 도망쳤죠
Alex ended up in a French
hospital, and I barely escaped.
그렇지만 궁에서는
너를 지목했잖아
But someone at the palace
pointed the finger at you.
모두가 너한테 박스가
있다고 생각했다고
Everyone thought
you had the box.
I didn't correct them.
정정하지 않은 거죠
그랬겠지, 길바닥 명성이
높아졌을테니까
Sure. It gave you
great street cred.
I came back to New York.
뉴욕으로 돌아왔어요
케이트는 없었고
Kate was gone.
저한테 배운게 있으니
Well, she learned
something from me,
사라지고도 남았죠
'cause she disappeared.
I started running big cons.
전 큰 건수를
치기 시작했어요
Guess I was trying
to get her attention.
케이트의 관심을
끌고 싶었나봐요
Well, you certainly got ours,
우리 관심은 끌었지
스티브 태너바클
Steve Tabernackle.
You knew about Steve?
스티브도 아세요?
많은 걸 알고 있었지
We knew a lot of things.
뉴욕으로 돌아오기 전에
Before returning to New York,
카프리는 덴마크,
프랑스에 나타났어
Caffrey popped up
in Denmark and France.
국경을 넘나드는 걸
두려워하지 않아
He's not afraid
to cross borders.
자기 일은 확실히 하네요
He definitely
does his homework.
국경관문마다
가명을 쫙 뿌렸으니
We flagged his aliases
at all ports of entry.
걸리기만 하면
바리케이드를 치죠
I mean, when we get a hit,
we throw up roadblocks.
아냐, 놈은 같은 이름은
두번 쓰지 않아
No, he'll never use
the same I.D. twice.
내가 못들은 걸
이야기 해봐
Tell me something
I haven't heard.
What about you?
자네는 어때?
이름이...
Agent...
Berrigan.
베리건입니다
You're on the run.
How do I catch you?
자네가 도망다니면
어떻게 잡아야겠어?
Stake out my girlfriend?
제 여자친구 집에서
잠복근무를 하겠죠?
카프리도 여자친구
있지 않습니까?
Well, Caffrey has one, right?
헤어진 것 같던데
We think they split up.
어딨는 지는 알죠
Well, but we know where she is.
- 우리가 감시하는 거 아나?
- 아니요
Does she know we're onto her?
No.
잡아들이기엔
증거가 부족해서요
We've never had enough
on her to bring her in.
그런데도 가까이
가지 않았단 말이지
And he hasn't gone
anywhere near her.
잠깐만
Hang on.
따라잡는데 몇 달이 걸렸고
It took us months to catch her,
일주일 이상 같은 데서
머무르지도 않아
and she never stays in the same
place for more than a week.
놈을 피해 숨어있는 거지
She's hiding from him.
He doesn't know where she is.
놈도 어딨는지 모르는 거야
Hey, Ruby's in Burma.
루비는 버마에 있대
가려면 경비행기가...
I'm gonna need
a bush plane to get...
이런
Oh, no.
비둘기 죽었어?
Did your pigeon die?
에스텔은 괜찮아
뉴욕 제일가는 비둘기니
No, Estelle's fine...
best homer in the city.
그럼 뭔데?
Then what?
I received some news.
소식을 좀 들었어
Some...information has surfaced
on the street.
어떤... 정보가 거리에서
돌아다니더라고
케이트?
Kate?
이해해야해
Y-you have to understand.
It comes from a highly
unreliable source.
굉장히 신뢰하기 힘든
제공자로부터 나왔거든
Where is she?
어디?
밀고자 지미라니까
His name is Jimmy the Snitch.
위치를 말해
I need a location.
닐, 함정 같다고
Neal, this smells like a trap.
상관 없어
꼭 봐야겠다고
I don't care.
I need to see her.
It's a storage facility.
창고 시설이야
오늘 오후에 올 거래
She'll be there this afternoon.
All right. Thanks.
그래, 고마워
Neal.
닐
Be careful.
조심해
Forging Raphael.
라파엘로를 위조하다니
You've gotten good.
실력 좋아졌네
진품이 도난당했다더라
I heard the real painting
was stolen.
네 관심을 끌거라고
생각했거든
I hoped it would get
your attention.
It did.
그랬어
보고싶었어
I missed you.
I lied to you
about a lot of things, Kate,
너한테 많은 거짓말을
했지만, 케이트
널 사랑한단 말은
거짓말이 아니었어
but I never lied
about loving you.
I believe you.
믿어
I love you, too.
나도 사랑해
How did you find me?
날 어떻게 찾았어?
모지가 너 모리셔스
우표를 팔고 있다길래
Well, Moz heard you were fencing
Mauritian penny stamps.
I quit dealing in stamps.
나 그 일 그만뒀는데
It's okay.
괜찮아
FBI다! 손 들어!
FBI!
Hands on your head!
버크 요원님
Agent Burke.
닐 카프리, 널 체포한다
Neal Caffrey.
You're under arrest.
I know.
압니다
Thank you.
고맙습니다
I never would have found her
without you.
요원님 아니었으면
찾지 못했을 거에요
It's my pleasure.
천만에
So you guys were all
in that municipal van out front?
앞에 있던 밴에
전부 타고 계셨어요?
불편하셨겠네요
That's got to be uncomfortable.
냄새도 별로 안 좋죠
Doesn't smell too good, either.
And you know the rest.
나머지는 아시잖아요
All right,
so what do we do next?
자, 이제 어쩌죠?
애들러를 찾아야지
이 모든 일의 중심이니까
We find Adler. He's the key
to this whole damn thing.
저도 찾아봤어요
Well, I've looked.
흔적이 오래된게 아녜요
아예 없다고요
His trail didn't go cold, Peter.
There is no trail.
I caught you when I found out
what you wanted most.
네가 가장 원하는 걸
찾았을 때 널 잡았잖아
놈이 뭘 가장 원하는 지 알잖아
We know what he wants most.
프랙탈이요
The fractal.
그래
Yeah.
이게 뭔데?
What is this?
뭐 생각나는 거 있으세요?
You have any ideas?
It must mean something,
must point somewhere.
뭔가를 의미할 거야
어딘가를 가리킬 거라고
Are you telling me
the truth, Neal?
사실대로 말하는 거 맞냐, 닐?
왜 물으세요?
Why do you ask?
I only know one of your friends
who's into origami.
네 친구 중에 종이접기
좋아하는 사람은 하나니까
알렉스가 다녀갔지
Alex has been here.
영수증은 오늘 날짜고
And this receipt is from today.
What does she think it is?
알렉스는 뭐라고
생각하는 건데?
It's a fractal antenna.
프랙탈 안테나요
They're in everything now.
요새는 어디에나 있죠
요원님 전화에도 있고요
There's one in your cellphone.
이 형태는 특정 주파수와
반응하는 거에요
And this shape corresponds
to a specific frequency
for an emergency beacon.
비상 신호기 용으로요
Emergency beacon?
Mm-hmm.
비상 신호기?
실제로 이걸 만들어서
You're telling me that if
we build a real one of these
무전기에 연결하면
and we hook that up
to a radio...
배나 비행기나
It's gonna lead us
to a boat or a plane
40년대에 없어진
뭔가로 이끌거란 거죠
or something that disappeared
in the 1940s.
두 사람을 죽일 정도로
값진 물건이라는 거군
Something worth
killing two people,
이 모든 일을 감수할만큼?
something worth all this?
애들러한테는요
It's worth it to Adler.
그럼 우리가 먼저
찾아야겠구나
Then I guess
we have to find it first.
S02E11 Forging Bonds
한글자막 DC 미드갤 SNL
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com